Daniel Coxon

Phone: 085-286-4262 Email: dancoxon37@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/dancoxonprofile

SUMMARY

Developed many systems and programs since starting college using Java as a main coding language. Also, designed and developed many web based applications using HTML, CSS and the JavaPlay Framework. Interested in increasing knowledge on the use of data in real world applications. Ambitious to gain experience in work environments, putting these skills to practice and to continue learning.

IT SKILLS

- Confident user of Java using Netbeans IDE
- Can design and develop software based on specification (Java)
- Can design and create database schemas
- Capable of designing developing websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Twitter Bootstrap, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA
- Competent user of Windows and Windows Command Prompt

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2015 - 2019 BSc (Hons) Computing

Institute of Technology Tallaght, Dublin 24

4th Year: GPA: 3.02

| Semester 8 | | Semester 7 | |
|--|----|--|----|
| IT Governance and Quality | В | Interactive Media Design & Visualisation | В |
| E-Learning | B+ | Information Management | B+ |
| Advanced Cloud Provisioning & Networking | C+ | Social Media Analysis | B+ |
| Operations Research | В | Private Cloud Architecture | В- |
| 4 th Year Project (Final) | В | Enterprise Performance Architecture | В |
| | | Security for Cloud & IoT | C+ |
| | | 4 th Year Project (Research) | В |
| | | | |

3rd Year: GPA: 2.32

| Semester 6 | | Semester 5 | |
|--|----|--|----|
| Experiential Learning (Work Placement) | B- | Networking 3 | C |
| Industry Project | B- | Advanced Databases | C |
| | | Web Application Development | C |
| | | Operating Systems | C |
| | | Innovation & Entrepreneurship | C+ |
| | | Cloud Services & Distributed Computing | В |
| | | 1 0 | |
| | | | |

2013 - 2015 HND in Contemporary Music Performance.

Ballyfermot College of Further Education, Dublin 10

2013 - Leaving Certificate

Holy Family Community School, Rathcoole, Dublin.

SIGNIFICANT PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN

4th Year Project:

This project was based around Rule-Based Interactive Chatbots, the variety of platforms available to develop them and their use cases. The final iteration of this project was developed using Dialogflow. Functionality of the chatbot included, allowing users to book restaurant table, taking their name, date of choice, time of choice, number of guests they wish to book for and storing them in a backend database. The database that was used for this storage is Google's Firebase 'Realtime Database'.

Other functionality included being able to view a food menu, which was pulled from the database, and place a food order. This order was then stored in the database. Users could also review their booking information or cancel their booking which removed all their data from the database.

This project was broken into three iterations, iteration two used a competing platform to Dialogflow called 'Amazon Lex'. The aim of iteration two was to compare the two development platforms after building similar systems on each.

Challenges faced & overcome:

- · Researching, learning and working with new technologies
- Database implementation & bug fixing
- Meeting multiple deadlines across two semesters

Technologies & Tools Used:

Google Dialogflow, JavaScript + Cloud Functions, Firebase Realtime Database, Amazon Lex + Lambda Functions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

January 2018 – July 2018 Internship Graphic Mint UX Design Agency, Dublin Ireland.

- Web Development Support
- Marketing Communications
- UX/UI Design & Development

June 2016 – Present Musician

- Playing gigs in various venues around Dublin
- Crowd interaction/entertainment

May 2015 – June 2016 Restaurant Staff

An Poitin Stil, Dublin Ireland.

- Working in fast paced high stress kitchen environment
- Liaising directly with chefs/management
- Serving customers in the restaurant

INTERESTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Sporting

 Member of club and school basketball team from 2005 – 2013. Participated in and won many tournaments around Ireland.

Musical

 Placed first in multiple music competitions and currently using my talent and qualification as a part time job. Have also used this skill to travel and work. For example, summer of 2016 was spent living in Spain and supporting myself by playing multiple gigs, meeting many different people and enjoying the experience.

Posts of responsibility

 Volunteer member of the local youth club, helping to organize and participate in many events over the years including trips to Peamount Hospital where we did musical performances and weekends away to Glendalough and Wales. 2007 – 2012.

REFERENCES

Available on request